

Gabriel Méndez Reyes

Software Engineer

Proactive software engineer focused on the front-end with more than two years of experience in this field. Consider myself a person with strong problem-solving skills that deliver business value through software. Focused and dedicated on best practices, design patterns, and agile methodologies.

Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

in linkedin.com/in/gabrielmndz

. +1 829-643-2322

19 July, 1998

github.com/GaboMendez

EDUCATION

University Degree

Technological Institute of Santo Domingo

08/2016 - 04/2020

3.7 GPA

Program

Software Engineering

Technical High School

Salesian Technical Institute ITESA

08/2012 - 05/2016 3.6 GPA

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Xpert Code / Claro Dominicana

08/2020 - Present Dominican Republic

Outsourcing for Xpert Code company at Claro IT Department

Tasks

- Full-Stack in ReactJS and Java Spring technologies.
- CI / CD in Jenkins and Openshift technologies.
- Management of agile SCRUM methodology.

Contact: Daniel Peña - 1829-988-8135

Mobile Developer

Caribe Media / Claro Dominicana

02/2020 - 07/2020 Dominican Republic

Outsourcing for Caribe Media company at Claro IT Department

Tasks

- Front-End in Xamarin Forms and Kotlin technologies.
- Modifying a software application made with Xamarin Forms to fix errors or upgrade user interfaces.
- Create user stories, manage issues, and communicate with the team through Azure DevOps.

Contact: Francis Zorrilla - 1809-350-3756

Mobile Developer Agua Planeta Azul

10/2019 - 02/2020

Dominican Republic

Working at the company IT Department

Tasks

- Front-End in the technology of Xamarin Forms.
- Writing and implementing efficient code implementing design pattern.
- Develop new functionalities in the application based on client's requirements.

Contact: Sergio Ceballos - 1809-444-3777

SKILLS

React Xamarin Forms Kotlin Git

JavaScript TypeScript HTML CSS

RESTful API Oracle Java C#

PROJECTS

Beekeeper (08/2019 - 04/2020) 🗗

- Developed in ReactJS and .NET Core technologies.
- It's a software dedicated to the control of attendance of university students.
- My participation in this project was the front-end development and activities such as the design and implementation of the database.

CERTIFICATES

Kotlin Development by KeepCoding (04/2020) ✓

Big Data Diploma by MESCYT (09/2019 - 12/2019)
Knowledge related to Big Data in the EOI

Web development with HTML/CSS/JS by MESCYT (08/2019 - 11/2019) ☑

Development of pages with HTML CSS and JQuery

Database Administrator (06/2019)

Web Development with C# Language by MESCYT (10/2018 - 01/2019) ☑

Development of WebForms and MVC pages with .NET

English Immersion Program by MESCYT (01/2017 - 11/2017) ☑

Microsoft Office Specialist Office Power Point (08/2015 - 05/2016) ♂

LANGUAGES

Spanisn

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Professional Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Software Development

Front-End Development

UI/UX

API Services

Data Structures

Design Patterns

Agile Methodologies